{
  "reference_number": "8024",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "It's too late! We must take action now. 2050 is it. If we do not change our situation by then, it will be too late to reverse the climate of\n our planet. The plan should be strictly set out so that there is no need to move the goal posts going forward. And if we come out\n\n ahead then woop!"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Get serious guys. There is no room for error here. The plan should be strictly set out so that there is no need to move the goal posts\n\n going forward. And if we come out ahead then woop!"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "Get serious guys. There is no room for error here. Too bad if the politics don't align, this is bigger than politics. The plan should be\n strictly set out so that there is no need to move the goal posts going forward. And if we come out ahead then woop!"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Too bad if the politics don't align, this is bigger than politics. The plan should be strictly set out so that there is no need to move the\n\n goal posts going forward. And if we come out ahead then woop!"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Individuals and families should not be taxed unnecessarily - this should be industry tax and applied to those using public services\nsuch as rubbish disposal, public transport systems, fuel (private & public), water (private & public), etc... Install toll booths for major\n\ncities, yes there will be a big outcry but really, when you're only paying $2 each way it's nothing and ensures the correct people are\nbeing targeted."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "So long as they are impartial, above reproach, publicly declare any conflicts of interest and submit to an annual financial audit to\n\nensure no corruption - all information (clearly not their actual financial situation but the outcome of the audit) to be made public."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": "The government (regardless of which party) needs to be separate to this, otherwise politics will destroy the only hope remaining."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Don't get too bogged down in cultural needs - sorry but we have very little time and a lot to do, too many chiefs will make this fall over."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "NOOOO!!!! That's just another way of giving us a back door. This WILL NOT work without full commitment."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "All organisations - not some - that's a loop hole that we all know people and organisations will utilise to get away with things as best\nthey can."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Do not f    this up guys! Take a leaf out of Danmark's book - they are a relative success story here. It's not like you have to reinvent\nthe wheel, just use what is already working.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
